

# Karsten Held M365 / SharePoint Berater IT Support Spezialist

Karsten Held Rothenburger Straße 32 D-01099 DRESDEN

+49 176 70861679

karstenheld3@gmail.com

www.karstenheld.com

in linkedin.com/in/karstenheld3

#### **Personal Profile**

A highly qualified and versatile consultant for SharePoint, M365, and GenAl with over 20 years of experience in IT support, software development, SharePoint architecture, and M365 solutions. Three years of experience as a SharePoint Admin and 3rd Level Support for the energy company Vattenfall. Worked in various industries, including finance, healthcare, telecommunications, and energy. Experienced in ITIL, solution architecture, full-stack development, and UX design. Leader of technical projects, trainer, and 3rd-Level Support specialist, with certifications in Microsoft technologies. Fluent in German, English, and Hungarian.

Available for freelance/contractor roles in SharePoint, M365, and GenAl development starting November 2024.

# **Areas of expertise**

- M365 3rd Level Support: System rollout and support, problem solving, escalation
- Trainings: End user trainings, SharePoint / Power Plattform online courses
- M365 & Power Platform: Power Apps, Power Automate, SharePoint-Integration
- SharePoint: Site-Provisioning, Governance, Webpart-Entwicklung, Migrationen
- Full-Stack Entwicklung: C#, TypeScript, React, EF Core, SQL
- Business Automation: Workflows, Datensynchronisation & Integration

# **Career History**



2019 – Now	External SharePoint /	′ M365 / GenAl /	/ Power Platform	Consultant at Vattenfall

- 2024 SharePoint integrated market intelligence solution with Azure Al Studio / Copilot Studio
- 2023 Power App for heating device installation deviations, SharePoint site provisioning solution
- 2022 SharePoint governance, migrations, tenant reporting, trainings / webinars, version clean-up
- 2021 SharePoint development projects, on-top-application support, Power Platform development
- 2019 2020 SharePoint technical service coordination, primary admin, 3rd level support

#### 2016 – 2019 External SharePoint / M365 Consultant / Developer at GASAG, Vattenfall, DHL, Telekom

- 2019 SharePoint / Power Platform event management solution with external mailing service
- 2018 Backend / frontend optimization of internal quote generation app (C#, EntityFramework, SQL)
- 2017 SharePoint / Excel based IT Security Self Assessment solution for DHL
- 2016 SharePoint Product Inventory Management System (JavaScript); Site Provisioning App (C#)

#### 2013 – 2015 Freelance Application Developer at M-Events, AUC, GEOMAGIC

- Mobile Application Development (iOS, AppGyver), Java Application Development (Vaadin)
- SharePoint Online Consulting, Office 365 and Email migrations

#### 2012 SharePoint Consultant at Communardo Software GmbH, Dresden

SharePoint 2013 Intranet-Solutions for <u>Axel Springer AG</u> and <u>Voestalpine Group</u>.

#### 2008 – 2012 Freelance Web Designer, Application Developer

Web-Development and Softwaretools for <u>Bencer</u>, Shanghai and <u>Osyon Gmbh</u>, Berlin

#### 2001 – 2008 Application Developer, Junior Fonds-Manager, Team Lead at <u>Vescore Solutions AG</u>

- 2006 2008 Developed central Asset Management Infrastructure (C#, VBA, Excel, Bloomberg)
- 2004 2006 Junior fund manger (Value, Private Equity)
- 2001 2004 App Development (Java, Swing, C#, WinForms, SOAP)

#### 2000 Software Developer at <u>Dr. Grob & Partner AG</u>, Winterthur

Developed Bridge and Tunnel Management System (Visual Basic 6, ORACLE)

Education

MCP Exams

2013 - 2015

Exam 331: Core Technologies for Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013

Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with Javascript and CSS3

Exam 488: Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Core Solutions

OCT 1994 – FEB 2000 Master of Civil Engineering (Dipl.-Ing) at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u>
OCT 1997 – FEB 2000 Studied Media Design at <u>Bauhaus-University Weimar</u> (no degree obtained).

**LANGUAGES** German, English, Hungarian



# **Karsten Held Factsheet**

**SharePoint Azure AI Studio Copilot Studio Azure AI Services** 

Expert
Advanced
Advanced
Advanced

**Power Apps Power Automate Azure Function Apps Azure Runbooks** 

Expert
Expert
Advanced
Advanced

Ty

Visit www.karstenheld.com for a detailed list of projects, customers and screenshots.

TypeScript	Advanced
C#	Advanced
PowerShell / PnP	Advanced
Python	Basic

# **Technology Experience**

#### **Programming Languages**

- C#, .NET Core, PowerShell
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- Java, VBA, Lua, PL/SQL
- Python
- Azure CLI

#### **Azure Services**

- Azure Al Studio / PromptFlow
- Azure Cognitive Search
- Azure OpenAl Service
- Azure API Management
- Azure App Registrations
- Azure Logic Apps
- Azure App Service
- Azure Runbooks
- Azure Functions
- Azure Storage Accounts
- Azure SQL
- Azure API Apps
- Azure CLI

#### **Custom Backends & APIs**

- SharePoint REST/CSOM API
- Dropbox REST API
- Bloomberg COM API
- Reuters COM API
- Datastream API
- Firebase REST API
- Google/Yahoo Finance REST

#### **Microsoft 365 Components**

- SharePoint Online
- **Power Automate**
- Power Apps
- Al Builder
- Copilot Studio
- **Power Pages**
- Power BI
- M365 CLI

#### **Development Tools**

- Azure DevOps
- Azure DevOps Pipelines
- VS Code, Visual Studio, ReSharper
- Git, GitHub, GitHub Copilot
- NPM/Yarn, NuGet, Chocolatey
- Grunt, Gulp, ESLint
- NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha + Chai
- ANTS, dotTrace, JProfiler
- TOAD, SQL\*Plus, SQL Developer

#### **Programming Concepts**

- Promises, Callbacks, Events
- Modules, Closures, Hoisting
- Lambda Expressions
- Generics, LINQ, Encoding
- **Object Oriented Programming**
- **Functional Programming**

#### On Premise Technologies

- Windows Server
- **Active Directory**
- MS SQL Server
- IIS (Internet Information Services)
- **Group Managed Service Accounts**

#### **UI Frameworks & Web Technologies**

- SPFx Framework (SharePoint)
- **Power Apps Component** Framework (PCF)
- React, JQuery, AngularJS, Sencha
- JSON Web Tokens
- CORS, GraphQL
- Blazor, SignalR
- HTML5, CSS3
- SVG, Canvas, Web Components
- Bootstrap
- WPF/XAML, WinForms
- Java Swing, Vaadin

#### Cryptography

- AES256, PBKDF2
- SHA256, HMAC
- Crypto.JS
- .NET/JAVA Cryptography

#### **Quality Management**

- SCRUM, JIRA, Youtrack
- ITIL, ISO 9001

#### **Services**



#### M365 App & 3rd Level Support

Support and maintenance of Microsoft 365 solutions: SharePoint, Power Apps, Power Automate, Copilot. System rollout, user communication, escalation management. Ticket analysis and reporting.



#### SharePoint Solutions

Information Architecture, Solution Design, Custom Collaboration Sites, Document Management Systems, Portals, Web Part Development, Integration with Azure Logic Apps or Power Automate.



#### Microsoft 365 App Development

Business Process Automation, Power App Development, Extranet Solutions using Power Pages, Al Builder, Microsoft Dataverse Backends, Power Apps Component Framework, Custom Connectors.



### Microsoft 365 Consulting

M365 Governance, Intranet solutions, Migration Projects, Data Loss Prevention, Retention Policies, Best Practices, Webinars, End-User Trainings, 3rd Level Support.